Do you like to bury your head in a good book?
你喜欢沉浸在一本好书里吗？
Getting absorbed in a good story is a great way to relax.
全身心投入一个精彩的故事，是一种绝佳的放松方式。
It improves your literacy, and, according to some experts, it’s good for your health as well.
阅读能提升你的读写能力，而且据一些专家称，它对健康也大有裨益。
Studies show that it can increase our emotional intelligence as we understand a range of perspectives and motivations.
研究表明，在阅读过程中，我们会了解到许多观点与动机，这有助于提高情商。
But despite these benefits, does the way we consume a story make any difference?
但抛开这些益处不谈，我们阅读故事的方式，是否会带来不一样的体验呢？
For the purist, the only way to digest a good story is with a paperback or hardback book.
对于纯粹主义者而言，品读一本好书的唯一方式，就是阅读平装书或精装书。
Being in print, it’s possible to feel and even smell the book. And of course it’s very portable.
纸质书可以触摸，甚至还能闻到纸张的气息，而且它的便携性也毋庸置疑。
But the traditional book has had a rival in recent years from e-books, which are read on e-readers or tablets.
但近年来，传统书籍遇到了一个竞争对手——电子书，这类书籍需要借助电子阅读器或平板电脑来阅读。
An ‘electronic’ book enables you to store hundreds of virtual books in one place and allows you to download books directly.
一本“电子”书能让你在同一个设备里储存数百本虚拟书籍，还支持直接下载。
The e-book has become popular in schools, too, and according to one school in London, it’s encouraged more children to read.
电子书在学校里也十分受欢迎，伦敦的一所学校表示，电子书激发了更多孩子去阅读。
11-year-old Summit told the BBC: “If you really want a book, you can just get it online.
11岁的萨米特在接受BBC采访时说：“如果你特别想看一本书，直接上网就能找到。
It’s so easy, and it’s made me read more.
这太方便了，也让我读了更多书。
I probably read every day now.”
我现在几乎每天都会阅读。”
For adults, e-books are certainly a lightweight way of accessing our favourite literature on the move.
对成年人来说，电子书无疑是一种轻便的方式，能让他们在出行途中随时阅读喜爱的文学作品。
The recent lockdowns due to the coronavirus pandemic have certainly given us all time to read more, and in the UK at least, sales of physical books have risen strongly.
近年来，新冠疫情引发的封锁让人们有了更多时间阅读，至少在英国，纸质书的销量大幅上涨。
Last year, some 202 million paperbacks and hardbacks were sold, and the publishing industry hopes this trend will continue now that people have got into the habit of reading more.
去年，平装书和精装书的销量约达2.02亿本，出版业希望，在人们养成了更频繁的阅读习惯后，这一趋势能够持续下去。
But for those who can’t or don’t want to look at the text in a book, there are audiobooks to listen to.
而对于那些无法或不愿阅读纸质文字的人来说，有声书是不错的选择。
According to Clare Thorpe, writing for the BBC Culture website: “There are hugely ambitious productions using ensemble casts, specially created soundscapes and technological advances… some authors are even skipping print and writing exclusive audio content.”
克莱尔·索普在为BBC文化频道撰稿时表示：“如今的有声书制作规模宏大，会启用全体配音阵容，搭配专门制作的音效场景，还融入了先进技术……有些作家甚至跳过纸质出版环节，直接创作独家有声内容。”
No matter what your reading preference, there’s no doubt we are spoilt for choice in how we access a good story.
无论你偏爱哪种阅读方式，毫无疑问，我们如今在接触精彩故事的途径上，已经有了太多选择。